where would you say the line needs to be
drawn um today between what is enhanced
interrogation and torture well if you
need special permission from the
director of the CIA to do something to
somebody you probably shouldn't be doing
it I always believed that there were
so-called enhanced interrogation
techniques that were worse than water
boarding for example uh the cold cell
you chill a cell to 50° and then every
hour throw ice water on the prisoner
who's naked uh people have died from
that Hassan Ghul died in Afghanistan
because of that technique and the other
one that I really objected to was sleep
deprivation Former Defense secretary
Rumsfeld made a joke that that he stands
on his feet longer than these uh these
Al-Qaeda uh prisoners were forced to
stand on their feet that's just simply
laughable we had people deprived of
sleep for as long as 2 weeks and in one
case one of the prisoners lost his mind
and was sub subsequently unable to
participate in his own defense because
of the sleep deprivation and what had
happened because of it right so it seems
like there are clear lines when you have
to ask for permission and when you when
you maybe are tapping into your
conscience and and realizing that this
is probably something I shouldn't be
doing that's really where the line
should be drawn that that's right and we
know we know from the Senate
intelligence uh committee's report uh
that that there were CIA officers who
were objecting to this from the very
beginning there were interrogators who
were told to carry out these techniques
who objected to them um and we also know
that the conclusions are true because
the Senate intelligence committee used
six million primary source documents
these are live realtime cables that CIA
officers were writing from the field and
sending to headquarters with the results
of the interrogation